苏珊・悉德尔曼作品
A Susan Seidelman Film
麦当娜 饰演 苏珊
Madonna as "Susan"
一位美丽的陌生女士，红头发，
绿色的新潮穿戴
"Beautiful stranger,
red hair, green jump suit,...
在华盛顿广场公园迁狗走过。
...walking dogs
in Washington Square Park."
我忘不了你，给爱一个机会吧。布莱克。
"Can't forget you. Give love a chance.
Blackie."
希望她给他一个机会。
Hope she gives him a chance.
哦，拜托，罗伯塔，这人肯定有点变态。
Oh, Roberta, please!
He must be some kind of a pervert!
-他可能是真心的。
-没有叫布莱克的是真心的。
- He could be sincere.
- Nobody named Blackie is sincere.
他不能忘了她，他在相思。这就很棒。
He can't forget her, he's in love.
It's great.
你不是正在读招聘广告吗？
Weren't you reading the want ads?
是的，我知道。
只是，好像找不到什么。
I know, I was.
I just... can't seem to find anything.
不要接受50,000以下的工作。
Don't settle for anything under 50,000.
-嗨，女士们！
-嗨，艾德里安，你觉得怎么样？
- Hi, ladies!
- Hi, Adrian. What do you think?
-罗伯塔，这才是你。
-我其实只想修剪一下。
- (woman) Roberta, the look is you.
- I just really wanted a trim.
不行，这是你的生日礼物。
No, this is your birthday present.
我要给你点不同的东西。
I want give you something different.
艾德里安，给她点有特点的，不奇怪的…
Give her something different, not weird...
放心吧，她丈夫会喜欢的。
(Adrian)
Don't worry. Her husband'll love it.
-哇，在这儿呢，吉姆的消息。
-啊？
- Wow, here it is! A message from Jim!
- Huh?
不顾一切找苏珊，决不动摇。
"Desperately seeking Susan.
Keep the faith."
星期二上午10点，巴特利公园，1号通道，相思的吉姆。
"Tuesday 10am. Battery Park,
Gangway one. Love Jim."
-谁是吉姆？
-哦，天啊，就是明天。
- Who's Jim?
- Oh, God, that's tomorrow.
谁是苏珊？你认识这些人？
Who's Susan? You know these people?
不是。吉姆全国上下的追随苏珊。
No. Jim follows Susan
all over the country.
今年一月她在墨西哥城，然后在西雅图。
Last January she was in Mexico City,
then Seattle.
他们发送来往的消息，这样他们能联系。
They send messages back and forth,
that's how they hook up.
现在他们在纽约。
Now they're in New York.
不顾一切，我喜欢这个词，太浪漫了。
Desperate. I love that word.
It's so romantic.
我认识的每个人都不顾一切，除了你。
Everybody I know is desperate
except you.
-我是不顾一切的。
-就你？！
- I'm desperate.
- You?!
呃，某种意义上。
Well... sort of.
《迫切》
(# "Urgent" by Junior Walker)
寻找苏珊\神秘约会\不顾一切找苏珊
Desperately Seeking Susan
你不害羞
# You're not shy
你总有招数
# You get around
你渴望飞翔
# You wanna fly
从不脚踏实处
# Don't want your feet on the ground
你高高在上
# You stay up
不愿下降
# Won't come down
你渴望生活
# You wanna live
在音乐之中畅想
# Wanna move to the sound
把热情释放释放
# Got fire
到你的血脉之中
# In your veins
被锻造得坚强
# Burning hard
你不会感觉一样
# Girl, you don't feel the same
你的渴望
# Your desires
那是疯狂
# Are insane
你不会停下
# You won't stop
除非你再次做它
# Until you do it again
有时我想知道
# Sometimes I wonder
当我看你的眼睛
# As I look in your eyes
也许你会想到
# Maybe you're thinking
另外的家伙
# Of some other guy
但我从来不知道…
# But I don't ever know...
服务生
Room service!
开着的！
(woman) It's open!
笑一个。
Smile.
- Hi.
你的报纸和龙舌兰酒。
I got you a newspaper and your tequila.
-谢谢。
-不客气。
- Thanks.
- You're welcome.
-你想放哪？
-这就行。
- Where do you want it?
- That's fine.
别全花在一个地方。
Don't spend it all in one place.
我不会，谢谢。
I won't. Thanks.
编剧
莱奥拉・拜丽斯
Written by
Leora Barish
导演
苏珊・悉德尔曼
Directed by
Susan Seidelman
吉姆！
Jimmy!
到时间了！
It's about time!
漂亮
Nice!
再见，布鲁斯
Bye-bye, Bruce.
还行吧，啊？
It was fun, huh?
电梯铃声
(lift bell)
请别关电梯
(woman) Hold the elevator!
就一会儿
(woman) Wait a second!
你属于我
(# "You Belong To Me" by Carly Simon)
罗伯塔，别让我吃那些东西，它们太好吃了。
Roberta, don't let me eat these.
They're so good!
嗨，我想我找到一个。
Hey, I think I've found one.
-一个什么？
-上楼，过来。
- One of what?
- upstairs. Come on.
他正晚上都盯着我。
He's been giving me the eye all night.
他是谁？
-哪个？
- Who is he?
- Who?
-角落里的，加里旁边的
-赖瑞・斯特曼
- In the corner, near Gary.
- Larry Stillman.
-斯特曼医生
-是教授是医生？
- Dr Stillman.
- Plastic surgery?
加里的牙医。
He's Gary's dentist.
嗯，至少不是哲学博士。
Well, at least he's not a PhD.
-加里，你朋友呢？
-你认识的，柏里。
- Gary, who's your friend?
- You know Becky.
哦！赖瑞・斯特曼…
Oh! Larry Stillman...
-我姐姐莱斯莉。
-你好。
- My sister Leslie.
- Hi, how you doin'?
你原来是牙医…
(Leslie) So you're a dentist...
-闹钟声
-哦，大家伙，时间到了！
- (watch beeps)
- Oh! Time out, everybody!
我要上电视了。
I've got a 10.58 spot.
-不错。
-真好。
- Oh, right!
- Great!
我台将会在女皇区有另一阶段进展的报道
Rosemary will have another instalment
of Growing up In Queens.
搜索最近抢劫古埃及文物案
The search continues for suspects...
的嫌疑犯的工作继续进行。
...in the recent robbery
of ancient Egyptian artefacts.
这一时段的新闻就报道到这里，下一新闻节目在11点。
That and more, next on the news at 11.
嗨，我是加里的绿洲的加里。
Hi. I'm Gary from Gary's Oasis.
在我们纽泽西的样品库里，
我们有数以百计的…
In our New Jersey showroom,
we have hundreds of models...
…浴池和浴盆样品，给您的都是出厂价。
...of whirlpools and hot tubs
at the lowest manufacturer-to-you prices.
快来加里的绿洲吧
So come on out to Gary's Oasis.
-我们节假日不休息。
-加里，进来吧。
- We're open seven days a week.
- Hey, Gary. Come on in!
在加里的绿洲，你会梦想成真。
(TV) At Gary's Oasis
all your fantasizes can come true!
非常好。
(woman) Very good!
它过去了
It's gone for ever.
那快乐的，年轻的，迷人的表情，我所爱的
That funny, young, lost look... I loved.
它一去不复返了
It won't ever come back.
当我告诉你丽贝塔时我已经杀了她
I killed that
when I told you about Rebecca.
你可以在床上带着耳机看。
You can watch in the bedroom
with the headphones.
我知道。
I know.
加里，
Gary,...
你是一直记得你的梦想吗？
...do you ever remember your dreams?
不知道，我从来没想过
I dunno, I never thought about it.
他们喜欢那个广告，你觉得呢？
They liked the commercial,
don't you think?
每个人都觉得你很棒。
Everyone thought you were great.
哦，你明天要…
Oh, you're gonna...
…修理我汽车的收音机，是吗？
...pick up the radio for the car
for me tomorrow, aren't you?
是。
Sure.
哦，别忘了…
Oh, don't forget...
告诉伙计你是我妻子，因为我们
在物主房间里放了一个烫发器
Tell the guy you're my wife because we
put a sauna in the owner's apartment...
他会给我们一个好价钱。
...and he's giving us a really great price.
晚安，宝贝
Night, hon.
听着，别把蛋糕全吃了！
Hey! Don't eat all that cake!
-苏珊
-嗨
- Susan!
- Hi.
我天，我们都以为你死了！
My God, we all thought you were dead!
没，不过在纽泽西罢了。
No, just in New Jersey.
鼓声
(drum roll)
乐队演奏
(band strikes up)
让我们听吧，女士们先生们，
这是蓝，传说中的蓝
Let's hear it, ladies and gentlemen,
for lan, the fabulous lan,...
还有他的最爱的助手水晶玻璃！
...and his lovely assistant Crystal!
嗨
(Susan) Hi.
-苏珊！你去哪了？
-哪都去。
- Susan! Where have you been?
- All over.
-每个人都知道吗？
-不是。
- Anybody I know?
- No.
一个大西洋城的人
Some guy from Atlantic City.
在他变认真之前很有趣。
It was fun till he started getting serious.
-最近怎么样？
-说真的，我真想辞职。
- How's tricks?
- I'm ready to quit this dump. I really am.
雷不让我带眼镜…
Ray won't let me wear my glasses,...
所以当我不能配合时蓝就大怒。
...then lan gets pissed off
when I can't do the tricks.
我是说，我真的看不见啊！
I mean, I'm only legally blind!
我可以理解，如果我把眼镜戴在乳房上…
I could understand
if I wore my glasses on my tits,...
…那就不会有人看我的脸了。
...but nobody here looks at my face!
拜托，离开这地方吧。
Come on, let's just get outta here.
-我必须去做那只消失的蓝鸟。
-听起来不错。
- I have to do the Disappearing Bluebird.
- Sounds great.
-你不能等等？
-我真的累了。
- Can't you wait?
- I'm really tired.
我可以叫一些皮萨在家中等你。
I could get some pizza
and meet you at home.
-你找到一个地方了？
-不算是。
- You've got a place?
- Not exactly.
只是我在那里工作。
But I'm working on it.
哦，不，我知道你要说什么了。
Oh, no. I know what's coming now.
我保证，就今晚。
Just for tonight, I promise.
求你了。
Come on!
你能保证电话只响七次吗？
Do you promise
only seven-digit phone calls?
发誓。你不会后悔的。
Cross my heart. You won't regret it.
多谢。
Thanks.
欢迎回来。
Welcome back.
待会儿见。
I'll see you later.
嗨，美人儿，拿一张报纸吧。
Hey, baby. Take a paper.
哇，怎么这样。
Wow, I don't believe it.
大西洋城治安环境暴降
暴徒从旅店窗户上落下
ATLANTIC CITY PLUNGE
MOBSTER FALLS FROM HOTEL WINDOW
靠！
Shit!
鼓声
(drumming)
打扰！
(man) Excuse me!
-有火吗？
-没有，我不抽烟。
- You got a light?
- No, I don't smoke.
苏珊！
Susan!
你怎么不对我说一声再见就离开了？
How come you split
without saying goodbye in person?
每个人见面了都说再见。
Everybody says goodbye in person.
来吧，一起喝一杯。
Come on. Let's go get a drink.
可以，但是只能一会儿。
um, yeah, OK,
but I've only got a few minutes.
-哦，别这样…
-已经是最后的准备工作。
- Oh, great...
- It's a last-minute thing.
今晚我们在Buffalo做一次演唱会。
The band got this gig in Buffalo
and we start tonight.
下次别在报纸上登广告了，行吗？
Next time don't put
an ad in the paper, OK?
苏珊，我每周都在找你。
Susan, I've been looking for you
for weeks!
陪我去Buffalo吧？
Come to Buffalo with me?
嗯，你可是在工作。
uh-uh, you'll be working.
-无聊的工作
-陪我去吧。
- (Susan) It's boring.
- Come to Buffalo.
我不会让你闲着无聊的。
(Jim) I'll find some trouble
for you to get into.
我现在已经没闲心了。
I've had enough trouble already.
你…你和这人睡过？
You... you were with this guy?
我离开时他还活着。
He was breathing when I left.
嗨，你们美女和野兽两位，
我可不想在桥上出事，快走！
Hey! Beauty and the Beast,
we'll hit traffic on the bridge. Let's fly!
《生之欲》
(# "Lust For Life" by lggy Pop on radio)
我不能就这样离开你。
I don't like leaving you like this.
-我能照顾好自己。
-好吧。
- I can take care of myself.
- I know.
这样，我给你一个电话…
Look, I'll give you a number. uh...
有笔吗？
You got a pen?
好了，这是我朋友迪兹的电话。
All right, this is the number
of my friend Dez.
他人不错…
He's a great guy...
…如果你有困难了就打给他，他知道怎么联系我。
...and if you really get in a jam, call him.
He'll know how to reach me.
-他有钱吗？
-别想了，他知道你是什么人。
- Has he got any money?
- Forget it! He knows all about you.
Johnny Yen又来了，
# Here comes Johnny Yen again
带着酒和毒品，
# With the liquor and drugs
还有绞肉机
# And the flesh machine
别寻刺激了，好吗？
No more dead bodies, OK?
我要看看我能干出什么来。
I'll see what I can do.
下次我回来还在这里见面。
Be here next time when I get back.
自从上当后我就没有好转…
# And I been hurtin'
since I bought the gimmick...
来吧，宝贝！
Come on, baby!
注意看啊！
(vendor) Check it out!
嗨，宝贝，这太阳镜专为你准备的。
Hey, baby, I got
a pair of sunglasses just for you!
这帽子再适合你不过了。
This hat'll look great on you, baby.
照照镜子，好看吧？
Take a look in the mirror.
Beautiful, right?
十美元，便宜吧，十美元。
$10 for the set, all right? Ten bucks.
你买吗？你哪里走？
You gonna buy?
Hey, where you goin', babe?
站住！你拿了我的帽子知道吗？
Yo! Come back!
What are you doin' with my hat?
还给我眼镜，怎么回事啊？
Give me my glasses, babe!
What's the matter?
-哦，天，怎么会这样！
-对不起。
- Oh, man! I don't believe it!
- I'm sorry.
你在干什么？
What are you doin'?
-对不起。
-说句对不起就完了？
- I'm sorry.
- What do you mean, "sorry"? Hey!
抱歉！
Sorry!
《尊严》
(# "Respect" by Aretha Franklin
playing in shop)
我不想继续你的错误
# I ain't gonna do you wrong
当你离开
# While you're gone
我不想继续你的错误
# Ain't gonna do you wrong
因为我不想
# Cos I don't wanna
就是你回家时当我问起…
# All I'm askin'
…那一点点尊严
# Is for a little respect
when you come home
亲爱的，当你回家
# Baby, when you get home
我考虑给你
# I'm about to give you
所有的钱
# All of my money
# And all I'm askin'...
给我个面子吧，不要穿出去。
Do me a favour, baby.
Stay on the carpet, OK?
-挺好看的，是吧？
-是。
- They're great, aren't they?
- I know.
我想要了，但是65美元的价钱有点…
I gotta have 'em, but 65 bucks...
-那是定价。
-别管定价。
- That is the price.
- Forget it.
-我喜欢你这夹克。
-这是Jimi Hendrix（摇滚明星）的。
- I like the jacket.
- It used to belong to Jimi Hendrix.
但我愿意用夹克来换靴子。
But I bet he'd love it
if I swapped it for the boots.
成交。
Deal.
# Ooo, your kiss is
# Sweeter than honey
# And guess what?
# So is my money...
很招人喜欢，是吧？
Gorgeous, isn't it?
它曾经可是猫王的。
It used to belong to Elvis Presley.
-试一试吗？
-行。
- Wanna try it on?
- All right.
# Oh, a little respect
# Oh, hey! A little respect...
我们从鸡蛋开始
(TV) We start off with the eggs.
两个两个打，动作要快
These go very fast done two by two.
你可以在早晨做
And this you can do in the morning...
然后准备开始做菜。
...and get it all ready for baking.
我会用新方法来做。
I'm gonna bake it and then unmould it.
这有六个鸡蛋了。
There are your six eggs.
然后用打蛋器搅拌…
Those get beaten up a little bit
and then in goes...
嗨，罗伯塔
Hello, Roberta.
嗨，朱莉娅
Hello, Julia.
抱歉，主妇们，我不能在家吃晚饭。
Sorry, girls. I can't stay for dinner.
西德的人订了1500个浴盆
Some guy from West Germany's
got 1500 tubs...
他为人传统
...he can't get through customs.
我得在镇上陪他吃饭。
I gotta go have dinner with him in town.
就这一次，我抱歉，你能理解吗？
It just happened.
I'm sorry. You forgive me?
看起来挺有意思的。
Looks interesting too.
-选好了收音机了吗？
-收音机？
- Get a good deal on the radio?
- Radio?
-汽车上的。你去城里干嘛去了？
-哦，对了，收音机。
- Car radio. You just came from the city.
- Oh, my God, the radio.
-你忘了？
-不是。
- You forgot the radio?
- No!
嗯，对，是，我忘了。
um... Yeah, right, I guess I did.
你可以说你不吃晚饭了，而我却忙的不可开交。
You could have said
you didn't want dinner. I had to rush!
你忙什么了？你说你什么地方都没去。
You said you didn't go anywhere.
你穿的是什么？
What are you wearing?
夹克。曾经是Jimi Hendrix的夹克。
A jacket.
It used to belong to Jimi Hendrix.
你买了一个穿过的夹克？
怎么，我们是穷人吗？
You bought a used jacket?
What, are we poor?
你这是怎么啦？
What's going on here?
罗伯塔，我必须要去了。
Roberta, I gotta run! I'm late.
我们晚些再谈吧。
We'll talk later, all right?
晚些谈。
All right, we'll talk later?
Jimi Hendrix,是吗？
Jimi Hendrix, huh?
落地声
(clattering)
电视声
(TV continues)
警方寻找神秘女人
你卖了？
You sold it?
我落下了开储物柜的钥匙！
I had a key that was important.
I got my shit inside a locker.
-我卖了。
-我留下名字和电话。
- I sold it!
- I'll leave you my name and number.
动作好快，陌生人！
Good goin', stranger.
什么他妈的陌生人？
Well, what fuckin' stranger?!
大型通铺。这意味着尿裤子。
Festival seating. That means Portosans.
尿裤子就是站着撒尿，我不想站着撒尿。
Portosans means pissing with flies.
I'm not gonna piss with flies.
你们男人可以尿在瓶子里。
这算什么？木房子？
You guys can piss in bottles.
What the hell is this? Woodstock?
电话声
(phone rings)
-放映员
-迪兹，是我，吉姆。
- Projection.
- Dez, it's me. Jim.
等一会儿。
Hold on a second.
哦，我的天啊。
Jesus Christ!
我在Buffalo脱不了身，请你帮个忙，
是关于苏珊的。
I'm stuck in Buffalo and I need a favour.
It's about Susan.
是这样，她在大西洋城遇到的一个家伙
被人从旅店的窗户上扔了出去。
See, now some guy she met in Atlantic
City got pushed out of a hotel window.
这里太乱了，我没听见。
This sounds wild. I'm sorry I missed it.
迪兹，我没开玩笑。
This is serious, Dez.
现在，一个署名陌生人的家伙登出启事
要在巴特利公园见她
And now some guy's run an ad to meet
her in Battery Park, signed "a stranger".
这有点怪了，你能不能
It sounds weird.
Could you just go down there...
去看一下她安全吗？
...and make sure she's OK?
吉姆，维多利亚昨晚刚甩了我，
我心情糟透了。
Jim, Victoria split on me last night.
I'm in a shitty mood.
我没法立刻就变成你的童子军。
I'm not in the mood for being a boy scout
right now.
拜托了，迪兹，就耽误你半个小时。
Come on, Dez.
It'll take you half an hour.
-好了没有？
-马上就好，一秒钟就好。
- (man) Come on!
- Give me a chance here. One second.
起哄声
(booing)
-她在四点去见他。
-四点？那可要差不多一个小时！
- She's got to meet him at 4 o'clock.
- That's in less than an hour!
吉姆，我可是有工作的人！
Jim, I got a job here, you know!
我求你了。
This one favour.
即使我能找到人替我
Even if I could get someone
to fill in for me,...
可我连她长得什么样都不知道。
...I don't even know what she looks like.
听着，你不会找不到她的。
Look, you can't miss her.
她很好看，金发，还有，中等身材
She's incredibly pretty,
blonde hair, uh... medium height.
还有她穿着绿色的，上面画着金色的…
And she's got this green and gold jacket...
一个锥形，一只眼睛在上面，就像钞票上那样。
（共济会标志）你肯定能找到她。
...with a pyramid with an eye on top
like a dollar bill. You can't miss it.
-好吧，你要请我吃饭啊。
-行，多谢，我一定请你。
- All right, you owe me one.
- Great. Thanks, Dez, I appreciate it.
好的，再见。
OK, yeah. Bye.
我一辈子都在纽约。
I lived in New York all my life.
我们老去中餐馆，意餐馆
We used to have Chinese restaurants,
ltalian restaurants.
现在你去吃寿司。所有人都吃寿司。
Now you have these sushi restaurants.
Everyone goes for sushi.
寿司，我讨厌这东西。
Sushi... I hate the stuff.
我跟你说，尽管我有一天我买了一些，
Although, I tell you,
I had some the other day.
回家做了，还不错的，味道像鱼。
I took it home, I cooked it, it wasn't bad.
It tasted like fish.
鼓声
(drumming)
9块2.
$9.20.
给，不用找了。
Here, keep the change.
哇，这是什么？嗨，女士！
Whoa! Hey! What is that? Hey, lady!
嗨，女士！
Hey! Hey, lady!
这算什么？
What is this?
靠，刁民！
Oh, that's cute!
嗨
Hi.
我以前好像见过你。
You look like I've seen you
somewhere before.
-不，我想不是。
-我想是。
- No, I don't think so.
- Yeah, I think so.
-你现在在做什么事情吗？
-我在等人。
- You doin' anything right now?
- I'm waiting for someone.
-跟我走，小姐。
-你不明白，我必须去见一个人。
- Come with me, miss.
- I have to meet someone.
-我们谈谈出租车里的事情。
-她那里有我所有的东西。
- We'll talk about it in the car.
- She's got all my stuff.
她会给你他妈的打车费。
She'll give you the goddamn cab fare!
我也不想这样，可我也得生活。
(driver) I don't need this aggravation.
I work for a living.
想吃霸王餐，我知道法律。
Theft of services. I know the law.
嗨，打扰了，你喜欢吃糖吗？
Well, hi!
Excuse me, but do you like candy?
-我这有甜甜糖。
-不，谢谢。
- I got some Sugar Babies.
- No, thank you.
我久想谈一谈，我认识你在大西洋城的的男朋友。
I wanted to have a chat. I was very close
to your boyfriend in Atlantic City.
-不可能，我结婚了。
-我不这样想。
- No, no, no. I'm married.
- No, I don't think so!
苏珊？
Susan!
你有一对他给你的漂亮的耳环吗？
Did you wear the pretty earrings
he gave you?
-我们得谈谈，我的车就在附近。
-放开我！
- Let's have a chat. My car is over there.
- Let go of me!
-苏珊。
-让我走。
- Susan!
- Let go!
-罗伯塔尖叫
-苏珊！
- (Roberta screams)
- Susan!
苏珊？
(Dez) Susan?
苏珊
Susan?
-发生什么了？
-你怎么样？
- What happened?
- Are you OK?
我头疼。
My head hurts.
我是迪兹，吉姆的朋友。
I'm Dez. I'm a friend of Jim's.
吉姆？
Jim?
你男友吉姆。和你争吵的那人是谁？
Your boyfriend Jim.
Who was the guy hassling you?
-谁？
-刚刚跑掉的那人。
- Guy?
- The guy that just ran off.
-我不知道。
-你不知道？
- I dunno.
- You don't know?
-我不记得了。
-你记不起来了？
- I don't remember.
- You don't remember?
你还好吗？
Are you OK?
要不要去医院？
Do you wanna see a doctor?
-我还好。
-你还可以。
- I'm OK.
- You're OK.
她还好，散了吧。
She's OK. Show's over.
他跟我来的，她还好。
She's with me, she's OK.
要坐下吗？
Sit down?
你什么都不记得了吗？
Do you remember anything?
不知道。
I don't know.
你怎么到这儿来的？
How did you get here?
不知道。
I don't know.
你记不记得早餐吃得什么？
Do you remember
what you had for breakfast?
不知道。
I don't know.
你叫苏珊，记得吧？
You are Susan, aren't you?
-苏珊？
-不知道。
- Susan?
- You don't know.
好吧，我们这儿有什么？
All right, what do we have here?
没钱吗？
No purse?
你的口袋里是不是有一些东西？
Do you have anything in your pockets,
maybe?
是什么？
Is that it?
哦，现在我们得去某个地方。
Ah! Now we're getting someplace.
这是我的电话号码。
This is my phone number.
是吉姆给你的。
Jim must have given it to you.
这好像似曾相识。
This is like a dejavu.
你怎么能似曾相识？
你什么都记不起来了。
How can you have a dejavu
if you don't remember anything?
不不，我是说，一切都是似曾相识的。
No, no. I mean... this is all dejavu.
这是Port Authority储物柜的钥匙。
This is a Port Authority locker key.
我来告诉你吧，我要带着你赶紧去
Port Authority的储物柜。
I tell you what. I'm gonna
run you up to the Port Authority.
也许储物柜里有什么东西
可以让你想起来什么。
Maybe what's ever in the locker will
help you snap out of it. How's that?
-好的。
- OK.
走吧。
Let's go.
等一下。
Wait a minute.
你不是在哄我玩吧？
This isn't some sort of trick, is it?
-你什么意思？
-我是说，我听说过你的一些事。
- What do you mean?
- I mean I know a little bit about you, OK?
所以别玩我，因为我心情不好。
So don't even consider jerking me around
because I'm not in a great mood today.
行，我是说，我不会…
Sure, I mean, I wouldn't...
玩你。
...jerk you around.
我都不认识你。
I don't even know you.
你戴上这个。
You better wear this.
但愿里面是一些好东西。
I hope it's filled with something good.
这是什么
Look at this!
你把它塞得够满的了。
You sure do move around a lot, huh?
也许是吧。
Yeah, I guess.
这东西应该是耳环，对吧？
So this stuff does look familiar, right?
这完全不可理喻。
Well, it's not completely unfamiliar.
你知道吗，当我闭上眼睛，我看到一个金字塔。
You know, when I close my eyes
I see a pyramid.
一个金字塔？
A pyramid?
像你夹克上的那个？
Like on your jacket?
对，就是那个。
Oh, yeah. That must be what it is.
至少你没丢东西。你好点了吗？
At least you got everything.
I hope you're feeling better.
-你是不是好点了？
-是。
- You are feeling better?
- Yeah.
很好。那我走了。我得把小摩托换回去。
Good. I gotta go.
I gotta get that scooter back.
那么，我哪次再来见你？
So, uh... I'll see you around
maybe sometime, huh?
可能我和吉姆一块来。
Maybe, uh... I'll see you with Jim.
好吗？保重，再见。
OK? All right, take care! Bye.
拜。
Bye.
苏珊。
Susan!
你今晚有地方睡觉吗？
Have you got a place to sleep tonight?
你可以去我那里。
You can sleep at my place.
就一晚上，沙发上。
One night... on the couch.
但是别给我找事。
But I don't want any drama.
也别叫你的狐朋狗友来。
I don't want your friends coming over.
也别随便拿走什么东西。
And I want nothing disappearing
from my apartment. You got that?
咳嗽
(coughs)
你还是别抽了
Maybe you should quit?
是的。
Maybe.
-多谢！
-客气。
- Thanks.
- You're welcome.
你，出去。
OK, you. You're outta here.
耽误时间。
It's about time.
怎么回事。
I don't believe it.
抱歉，耽误你了吗？
Sorry, man. Have you been waiting?
-下次没机会了。
-你要明白，这事紧急情况。
- Never ever again!
- Listen, man, it was an emergency.
我明白，没机会了，下回别管我借了。
I understand. Never ever.
Don't ever ask me again.
-好吧。
-不好意思。
- OK.
- Sorry.
这边。
This way.
-这有人住？
-当然有人住。
- People live here?
- Yes, people live here!
抱歉，只不过我想这里有点不一样。
I just thought it was sort of unusual,
that's all.
得上两层。
Two flights up.
抱歉。
Oh! Sorry.
抱歉，借过。
Oh! Sorry, man. Excuse me.
他们替我宣扬了这儿有人住。
Those look exactly like my speakers.
嘿嘿，等一等。
Whoa, whoa, whoa! Wait a minute.
你在干什么？给我那个。
What do you think you're doing?
Give me that.
谢谢。
Thank you.
这儿他妈怎么了？
What the hell is goin' on here?
笑声。
(laughter)
不是吧。
I don't believe it.
你要干什么？
(man) What you've gotta do is...
不错啊，维多利亚。
(Dez) That's just great, Victoria.
迪兹，这是我的东西。
It's my stuff, Dez.
那你就来取了？
So you just come and take it.
没打个电话，也不商量，什么也没有
No phone call, no discussion,
no nothing.
-你好吗？
-还行。
- How you doin'?
- I'm fine.
这样，我把这些拿到
下面Porsche（德国跑车）上去。
Listen, uh... I'm gonna take
this stuff down to the Porsche.
我敢肯定有些东西是我的。
I believe some of that stuff is mine.
比如应答机，比如Charlie Parker的唱片。
Like the answering machine.
Like the Charlie Parker records.
-行啊，还你。
-谢谢。
- Oh, you can have it. Here.
- Thank you.
我会为其他的东西给你一张支票，好吗？
I'll send you a cheque for the rest, OK?
支票？行。
A cheque? Great.
-嗨
- Hi.
他是一个好小伙。
He's really a nice guy.
你一定会开心的。
You'll be happy together.
-抱歉。
-没事。
- Sorry.
- It's OK.
口哨声。
(Dez whistles)
其实，你可以打扫一下这地方。
You know...
you could do a lot with this place.
这儿很明亮。
There's a lot of light.
靠。
Ah, shit.
你是凑巧和人吵起来了，对吗？
It happens, right?
应答机。
(answerphone beeps)
嗨，迪兹，是我，吉姆
(answerphone)
Oh, hi, Dez. It's, uh... It's Jim here.
我刚打电话想知道苏珊怎么样了。
I'm just calling to see if Susan's OK.
我在…妈的，我这儿是在哪里。
I'm calling from, uh...
Oh, shit, I don't know where we are.
只知道是汽车旅馆，嘿，这地方叫什么？
It's some motel... Hey, where are we?
管他啦，这样吧，我明天打给你。
Anyway, no, look...
I'll call you tomorrow, OK?
多谢你了。
And thanks again for everything.
真够哥们，谢谢，拜。
You're a pal. Thanks a lot. OK, bye.
看来电话铃还要响几次。
That's gotta ring some bells.
-老实说，不是凑巧。
-不是？
- Honestly, no.
- No?
那糟了。
Terrific.
-我要喝一杯，你要点什么？
-都行。
- I need a drink. Do you want something?
- All right.
你有的，什么都行，苹果汁，可乐，梨子酒
Whatever you're having.
Apple juice. Coke. Perrier.
Miller还是Heineken（都是啤酒品牌）
Miller or a Heineken?
-都行。
-到底哪一个？
- All right.
- Which?
第一个。
Either one.
谢谢。
Please.
口哨
(Dez whistles)
搞错了吧！
(Dez) I don't believe it!
她把冰箱拿走了。
She took the refrigerator.
-警察怎么说？
-这种情况大多数在24小时内就能找到。
- What did the police say?
- Most of these cases turn up in 24 hours.
你告诉他们那夹克的事了吗？
还有她的结婚戒指在皂盒上？
Did you tell them about the jacket?
Her wedding ring in the soap dish?
我说了！
I told them!
他们怀疑她只是有什么事。
They seem to think she's having an affair.
哦，天啊，也许就是有事。
Oh, my God, maybe she is!
真是荒唐，罗伯塔哪来的事！
It's ridiculous.
Roberta is not having an affair!
-她太冷淡了。
-亏你说得出来
- She's much too uptight.
- That is a horrible thing to say.
我看你对和Becky Shuman偷情还挺得意的。
I suppose you're proud of the way you're
running around with Becky Shuman.
我不知道你在说什么，
总之，我们没偷情。
I didn't know you knew.
Anyway, we're not running around!
现在不是说闲话的时候！
We're having
a perfectly respectable affair!
-加里，让我问你点事。
-什么？
- Gary, let me ask you something.
- What?
罗伯塔有性高潮吗？我是说，和你做的时候。
Does Roberta have orgasms?
I mean, did she have them with you?
-高潮？
-你心里明白，对吧？
- Orgasms?
- You have heard of them, haven't you?
也许因为你不能给她满足她才走了。
Maybe she left you
because you weren't satisfying her.
莱斯莉，没人会痴迷于什么性高潮！
Leslie!
Not everybody is obsessed with orgasms!
-只是有些人…才有的。
-那么她呢？
- Some people just... have them.
- Did she?
-你和Phil Donshue谈论性高潮吗？
-你个蠢货！
- Did Phil Donahue discuss orgasms?!
- You are really a pig!
-至少我体验过。
-体验过。我也有！
- At least I know about feelings.
- Feelings. I feel! I feel!
你真恶心，跟你爸一样。怪不得罗伯塔离开你。
You're disgusting. You're just like Daddy!
No wonder Roberta left you.
你说够了吗！
Would you stop saying that!
-加里
-赖瑞
- Gary...
- Larry!
看着不错。有罗伯塔的消息吗？
That looks great.
Any word from Roberta yet?
这么快就搞上了，莱斯莉。
Fast work, Les.
哦，这里还有一些鸡肉。
Oh, let's have some chicken.
赖瑞，那是明天吃的。
The chicken is for tomorrow. Larry!
警察怎么说？
What did the police say?
出了这么大的事你们还吃东西！
I can't believe
you're eating during a crisis!
我们够紧张的了，你还要怎么样？
We're nervous!
那你们应该像个正常人那样去打镇定剂！
Then take a Valium like a normal person!
她有一口好牙。
She has great teeth.
这就是我为什么出现在巴特利公园
(Dez)
That's why I showed up at Battery Park.
吉姆说你的一个朋友摔死在
大西洋城的旅馆外边。
Jim said a friend of yours got killed
outside your hotel in Atlantic City.
他担心坏了。
He was pretty worried.
摔了？
Killed?
杀死了？
Dead?
这也是你的兴趣之一，是吗，苏珊？
Sort of goes with the territory,
doesn't it, Susan?
也许我知道是谁干的。
Maybe I know who did it.
我希望我能想起来。
I wish I could remember.
也许就是你杀的。
Maybe you were the killer.
不可能。
No! (laughs)
我想我要躺一会儿
I should probably lay low for while, huh?
好主意。
It might be a wise idea.
你不知道在码头的那个人是谁？
You don't know
who the guy at the quay was?
也许是被你抛弃的情人
Maybe a jilted lover?
肯定不是。
I don't think so.
也有可能。
Maybe he was.
你可知道
You know somethin'?
你不完全是我所想的那样。
You are not at all what I expected.
你也不全是我想的那样。
You're not quite what I expected either.
萨克斯
(sax ophone)
我怎么认识的吉姆？我是说…
Just how did I meet Jim? I mean, how...
我怎么遇到他的？
How did I meet him?
也许这个有帮助。
Maybe it would help.
我想是在那个咖啡店里。
I think it was at some coffee shop.
那是你工作的第一天，
It was your first day at work.
吉姆大摇大摆的进来。
Jim waltzed in.
你给他带来吃的，然后把帐单撕了。
You brought his food over
and you ripped up the check.
他个高吗？我说的是吉姆。
Is he tall? I mean Jim.
中等个头吧。
He's about medium.
哪种身材？
Is he sort of thin?
哪种，哪种，呃…
Sort of. Sort of, um...
跟我差不多。
...my build.
眼睛是什么颜色的？
What colour eyes does he have?
蓝的。
Blue.
跟你一样？
Like yours?
抱歉，抱歉。
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
抱歉。
(Roberta whispers) Sorry.
我不知道怎么回事，只是…
I don't know what happened. I just...
不好意思。
Sorry.
雷声
(thunder rumbles)
哼哼
(groans)
过来。
Come on.
迪兹
(whispers) Dez!
Dez...
和我一起吃早餐吗？
Wanna go out to breakfast with me?
早餐
Breakfast?
你怎么了？穿的有点恶心。
What have you got on?
Some sort of disguise?
-你不喜欢？
-不，只是，呃…
- You don't like it?
- No, it's, uh...
还是迷人的。
...sort of charming.
我请客。
It's my treat.
你要干嘛？抢银行？
What did you do? Rob a bank?
我不知道，也许吧。
I don't know. Maybe.
你要到哪里去？
Where do you wanna go?
看，我在手提箱找到这个。
See, I found this in the suitcase.
Gunny的咖啡店？我知道这地方。
Gunny's Coffee Shop? I know the place.
它在中央大街附近。
It's over on Center Street.
也许我就是在那儿遇见吉姆的。
Maybe that's the place where I met Jim.
-然后？
-然后…
- So?
- So...
然后我们就去那里
看看是否有人认识我。
So we go there
and see if anybody remembers me.
看得怎么样，有熟悉的吗？
So what do you think?
Anyone look familiar?
还没有。
No. Not yet.
我在手提箱里找到这个，你听说过吗？
I found this in the suitcase.
You ever hear of it?
魔术俱乐部？是的，在百老汇附近。
The Magic Club? Yeah.
That's that place over on Broadway.
怎么了？
Why?
我想我应该去那，看看有没有熟人。
I thought I'd go there
and see if I remember anyone.
-你知道你要点什么吗？
-当然。
- You know what you're having?
- Sure.
你要点什么？
What are you having?
嗯，是你请客，对吧？
Well, it's your treat, right?
是的，我付账。
(giggles) Yeah, I got money.
我要点…蓝莓点心。
I'm gonna have... blueberry blintzes.
很好，我也要那个。
I'll have that too. That sounds good.
你要点什么？
What can I get you?
呃，一杯咖啡。
Yes, I would like a... coffee...
还有…甜圈饼
...and a, uh... doughnut.
小姐，如果你有空了，就给我们上吃的吧。
Miss! When you get a chance,
could you take our order?
给你可以，她可不行。
You can stay. She's gotta go.
Mick，那个穿夹克的疯子女孩来了。
Mick, it's that crazy girl with the jacket.
-你，滚！
-你认识我？
- You, out!
- You know me?!
对，别想在这儿吃霸王餐。
Yeah. You won't get a free meal here.
-我有钱，我可以付款。
-我不要你的钱，滚出去。
- I got money, I can pay.
- I don't want your money. Get out.
-我们有钱，怎么了？
-想想你自己的事吧。
- We got money. What is it?
- Mind your own business.
-这就是我的事，等一下。
-过来，出去。
- This is my business, wait a minute!
- Come on, out!
-嘿，我和他一起的。
-出去，出去。
- Hey, I'm with her.
- Come on, come on.
你幸运去吧，我没向你逼帐！
You're lucky I don't press charges!
迪兹。
Dez.
你怎么样，还好吧？太对不起了。
Are you OK? Are you all right? I'm sorry!
我说的第一条规则就是别给我找事。
Rule number one was no drama.
-记得吗？
-是的，我知道，抱歉。
- Remember?
- Yes. I know. I'm sorry.
我们走吧。
Let's get out of here.
不好意思。
I'm sorry.
争吵声
(man and woman arguing)
你从来不让我戴眼镜。
(woman)
You won't even let me wear my glasses!
回去卖T去吧，你被解雇了！
(man) Go back to selling T-shirts!
You're fired!
不对，你错了，蓝，是我辞职不干了。
(shouts) No, you don't, lan, because I quit!
嘿，别在梯子下面！
(Susan) Hey! Not under the ladder!
我的命运绝不可能比这儿更糟糕的了。
败类人渣！
My luck can't get much worse anyway.
Miserable scumbags!
也许我应该在床上教训他。
Maybe I should've slept with him.
姐们，有个巫婆偷了我的衣服…
Man, some witch steals my clothes,...
…米克尔被人从旅店窗户扔了出去，
现在你又被炒了。
...Meeker gets pushed out a hotel window
and now you get fired.
不太糟，但是坏运气好像抓着你不放。
No offence, but bad luck really seems
to be following you around.
我们现在都清闲了，一起去看个电影吧。
We're both free now.
Let's just go to the movies.
两场连映的？
A double feature?
来吧。
Come on!
如果你请我吃爆米花的话，电影票就我买了。
I'll pay for the movie
if you pay for the popcorn.
可以，但是，爆米花多少钱？
OK, but listen. How much is popcorn?
-2.50
-行。
- 2.50
- OK.
笑
(giggling)
就是这地方。
This must be the place.
司机，靠边停吧，就是这儿。
Sir, could you pull over, please?
This is it.
真是不好意思。
I'm sorry about what happened.
-你没有生气吧？
-没。
- Are you sure you're not angry?
- Yeah.
-真的。
-我没生气。
- Really?
- I'm not angry.
你真够哥们。
OK. You're a real pal.
我会告诉吉姆的。
I'll tell Jim.
-拜
- Bye!
- Bye.
够哥们，我会告诉吉姆…
A real pal. I'll tell Jim...
布利克大街电影院
Bleecker Street Cinema.
你只是别再这样开除谁！
(man)
You just don't fire someone like that!
我上哪里去找这么文静的女孩去？
Who am I gonna find
at such short notice?
拜托，你认识那么多女孩。
Come on, Ray. You know lots of girls.
-很多女人都在找工作。
-妈，别打扰我。
- (woman) Plenty of women need work.
- (Ray) Ma! Let me take care of this.
你好。
Hello.
你看见外边的招工告示了？
You saw the sign outside?
你是在找工作？
Are you looking for a job?
是的，我想我是。
Yeah. Yeah, I think I am.
-她还在想她在找工作。
-不。
- She thinks she's looking for a job.
- No!
我是在找工作，是什么工作？
I am, I am! What kind of job?
进来吧。
Come on in.
这位是雷。
This is Ray.
-您好。
-这位是雷的妈妈，格蕾妲。
- Hello.
- This is Ray's mom, Gilda.
嗨。
Hi.
-这位是哈雷。
-嗨。
- This is Henry.
- Hi.
您好，哈雷。
Hello, Henry.
还有我，蓝。
And I'm lan.
收音机
(radio on)
加里先生，你还好吗？
Are you OK, Mr Glass?
还行，谢谢你。晚安，Daisy。
Fine, thank you. Good night, Daisy.
我希望加里夫人没事。
I hope you get good news
about Mrs Glass.
谢谢。
Thank you.
你拿这个包去哪？
Where did you get this bag?
它是我的，加里夫人把它给我了。
It's mine. Mrs Glass give it to me.
把包给我，Daisy。
Give me the bag, Daisy.
-Daisy，把包给我。
-对不起，这包是我的。
- Daisy, give me the bag!
- Sorry, you ain't getting this bag.
-请你给我，我要好好的问问你。
-这包是我的。
- Please, I'm asking you nicely.
- You're not getting this.
《笨蛋主持》
(# "Sucker MCs" by Run DMC
on ghetto blaster)
嘿，我说，你们能挪个地方吃东西吗？
Hey, guys. Could you, uh...
have your picnic somewhere else?
嘿，你们这些人！
Hey, guys!
好吧，
Right...
小心轻放，行吧？
Just try to be careful, all right?
听着，我不想卷入家庭纠纷，好吗。
Listen, I don't get involved
in domestic disputes, OK?
不是纠纷。
There's no dispute.
在她没有失踪前时，她穿着一件夹克。
She had the jacket on
when she disappeared.
某种原因上讲，这对她很不一样。
It was very special to her
for some reason.
你真的记不起来她了？
Don't you even remember her?
你也记不起来夹克了？
Don't you remember the jacket?
黑色的，上面还有一个金色的像金字塔的图形
It was black and gold and it had
a sort of a pyramid thing on it...
就像钞票上的那样。
...like on a dollar bill.
记不清了。
Vaguely.
很好，谢谢，你可真会帮忙。
Great. Thanks.
You've been a terrific help.
等等，等等。
Wait a minute, wait a minute.
她也来过这儿找夹克。
She stopped in here
looking for the jacket, too.
也许你们能互相帮助。
Maybe you can help each other.
电话铃
(phone rings)
苏珊，接一下电话。
Susan, will you get the phone?
电话铃
(ringing continues)
苏珊，电话！
Susan! The phone's ringing!
苏珊！
Susan!
你好。
Hello?
等下，她在这儿。
Yeah, hold on. She's right here.
-什么事？
-你的另一个暗恋者。
- What?
- Another one of your secret admirers.
喂？
Hello?
是，你是谁？
Yeah. Who is this?
加里・格兰斯？
Gary Glass?
嗯，嗯。
uh-huh.
哦，你就是巫婆的丈夫，我的东西呢？
Oh, so you're the witch's husband.
Where's my stuff?
嗯。
Yeah.
嗯。也许我能帮你。
Well, maybe I could help you.
听着，今晚10点30到西21世纪街30号去见我。
Listen, meet me tonight at 10.30
at 30, West 21st Street.
我在柜台边的第三个座位等你，听明白了？
I'll be waiting on the third floor
near the bar. You got that?
好的，再见。
All right, I'll see you there.
-嘿
-稀少的掌声
- Hey!
- (sparse applause)
晚上好，先生们女士们。
Good evening, ladies and gentlemen.
欢迎来到魔术俱乐部，
我是主持人，大雷。
Welcome to the Magic Club.
I'm your host, Big Ray.
今晚我们有一系列的好节目，为所有人准备的。
We have a wonderful line-up for you
this evening, for all you people.
你，先生，就是穿红色衬衫的…
You, sir, the man in the red shirt...
-你从哪来？
-从布兰克林。
- Where you from?
- (man) I'm from Brooklyn!
我们当中还有谁是从布兰克林来的吗？
Do we have anyone else here
from Brooklyn?
好的。为什么你们两个不在一个酒吧间里？
Right here.
Why don't you two share a cab home?
-笑
-真是好观众。
- (man laughs)
- This is a great audience.
好的，让我继续吧，我要介绍一位…
(Ray) OK, let's get on with it.
Introducing, back from his...
苏珊，过来。
Susan! Come here!
独一无二的，举世无双的，冉冉新星…
(Ray) The one, the only, the innovator...
从现在开始，我要你
在我们开始前在这儿呆五分钟。
From now on, I want you here
five minutes before we begin.
记住，我们从鸽子开始。你看起来很漂亮，要微笑。
Remember, we start with the doves.
You look beautiful. Smile.
Davina，今夜女王。
Davina... Queen of the Night!
所以，你们这些可爱的人们，
让我们欢呼吧，来吧！
So let's hear it
from all you lovely people. Come on!
掌声
(applause)
欢迎短曲
(band plays fanfare)
咳嗽
(Susan coughs)
口哨
(wolf whistle)
演奏
(band plays)
掌声
(applause)
薄荷，又长又薄。
(woman) Menthol, extra-long, ultra-thin!
又长又薄哦，老顾客，就不用我说了…
Extra-ultra long and thin!
Regular, unleaded...
鼓掌
(applause)
不要啊。
Please!
下来吧。
(Roberta) Come down!
Davina
(lan) Davina!
鼓声
(drum roll)
掌声
(applause)
谢幕。
Bow!
这一个比那一个还差！
This one's worse than the other one!
值得鼓励，孩子。
Nice try, kid.
给你的，20美元。
Here you go. 20 bucks.
明晚还是这个时间过来。
See you tomorrow night
at the same time.
-你雇佣我了？
-当然雇佣你了。
- You're hiring me?
- Well, of course we are!
谢谢。
Thank you!
把这些拿回家好好练习，好吗？
Take these guys home and practise,
all right?
还有，苏珊，多多练习，好吗？
And, Susan... practise a lot! OK?
-好的。
-很好。
- All right.
- Good.
《入轨》
麦当娜 唱
[歌词不译]
(# "Into The Groove" by Madonna)
# Get into the groove
# Boy, you've got to prove
# Your love to me, yeah
# Get up on your feet
# Yeah, step to the beat
# Boy, what will it be?
# Music can be such a revelation
# Dancing around
# You feel the sweet sensation
# We might be lovers
if the rhythm's right
# I hope this feeling never ends tonight
# Only when I'm dancing
can I feel this free
# At night I lock the doors
where no one else can see
# I'm tired of dancing here all by myself
# Tonight I wanna dance
with someone else
# Get into the groove
# Boy, you've got to prove
# Your love to me, yeah
# Get up on your feet
# Yeah, step to the beat
# Boy, what will it be?
# Gonna get to know you
in a special way...
加里，格兰斯，是吧？
Gary Glass, right?
是，你怎么知道？
Yeah, how did you know?
一猜便知。
Wild guess.
-她离你而去，啊？
-是，两天前。
- She split on you, huh?
- Yeah. Two days ago.
她之前离开过你吗？
Has she ever split on you before?
没，当然没有。
No, of course not.
-她嗑药吗？
-嗑药？罗伯塔？
- Did she do drugs?
- Drugs? Roberta?
她从小连大麻烟都没吸过。
She's never smoked a joint
in her whole life.
她可能是李堡（纽泽西）最规矩的人。
She's probably
the straightest person in Fort Lee.
你是什么意思？
What are you driving at?
-你要喝点什么？
-呃，不，谢谢了。
- Do you want something to drink?
- um... No, thanks.
我在计划健身，不喝酒，不吃甜的。
I'm on this health programme, you know?
No alcohol, no sugar...
-你要跳舞吗？
-跳舞？
- Do you wanna dance?
- Dance?
借过，借过。
Excuse me. Excuse me.
# Live out your fantasy
# Here with me
- # Just let the music set you free
- (Gary coughs)
你看了报纸上关于一个叫米克尔的家伙的事了么？
Did you read that stuff in the newspaper
about that guy Meeker?
他在大西洋城被人从旅店窗户上推了下去。
He got pushed out of a hotel window
in Atlantic City.
-没有，为什么？
-罗伯塔参加了这次谋杀。
- No, why?
- Roberta's mixed up in it.
罗伯塔？怎么可能！
Roberta? That's impossible!
真的。她为米克尔的谋杀而圈定了我。
Fact. She's trying to frame me
for Meeker's murder.
谁是米克尔？
Who's Meeker?
是谁？而且他和罗伯塔到底想干什么？
Who's Meeker and what does
he have to do with Roberta?
米克尔死前的同伙和罗伯塔，
两个人一起干的。
Ex-partner and Roberta
were in on it together.
我想你弄错了，
I-I think you're mistaken.
罗伯塔在大西洋城不认识什么人。
Roberta doesn't know anybody
in Atlantic City.
我看见他们在一起了。
I've seen them together!
你看了罗伯塔和别的男人在一起了？谁？
You saw Roberta with another man! Who?
在我来看就像是个油球。
Looks like a real greaseball to me.
你说的我都不信。
I don't believe a word you're saying.
相信我，你想找到你妻子吗？
Here, trust me. You wanna find your wife?
-使得，当然我要！
-很好，带我去你家。
- Yeah, of course I do!
- Good. Let's go to your place.
我家？
My place?
借过。
Excuse me.
# Now I know you're mine
打扰。
Excuse me!
先生。
Sir!
有人跟踪我。
There's someone following me.
求你了，你能…
Please! Could you... Could you...
有个男人，有个男人跟踪我…
There's a man...
There's a man following me...
你是怎么进来的？你不能到这里来。
How do you get in here?
You're not supposed to be in here.
我知道，对不起，先生，能帮我看一看他走了吗？
I know. I'm sorry, sir,
but could you please see if he's gone?
有个男人跟踪我，你可以看看他走了吗？
There's a man following me.
Could you see if he's gone?
-可以。
-谢谢。
- OK.
- Thank you.
你呆在这里。
You stay here.
Enrique会小心处理的。
Enrique will take care of it.
不错！
no mal!
不错。
Yeah.
电视声
(singing on TV)
# He's hot!
# Your body's hot
# You're always hot, all the time, hot...
# Oh, I'm so hot, oh!
# So hot!
嗨，我是加里的绿洲的加里。
（西班牙语）Soy Gary de Gary's Oasis.
在我们纽泽西的样品库里，
我们有数以百计的…
En nuestro local en New Jersey,...
…浴池和浴盆样品，给您的都是出厂价。
...tenemos cientos de ba ras calientes
a los precios m  bajos.
快来加里的绿洲吧，
As?que venga a Gary's Oasis,...
我们节假日不休息！
...abierto siete d s a la semana.
-来吧，加里。
-不，别这样。
- Hola, Gary!
- No, muchachas. No!
在加里的绿洲，你会美梦成真。
At Gary's Oasis
all your fantasies can come true!
升降声
(lift moves)
先生？
Sir?
先生！
Sir!
升降机接近声
(lift approaches)
出租车！出租车！
(screeches) Taxi! Taxi!
出租车！
Taxi!
喘息声
(gasps)
尖叫声
(screams)
-你自己送上门来了。
-等等，我给钱！
- You'll get yourself in a twist.
- Wait! I have money!
我的钱在我的包里！
I have money in my bag!
耳环，我要耳环。
OK. The earrings, I need them.
什么耳环？求求你，你搞错人了。
What earrings?
Look, I'm not who you think. Please.
好了，好了，别重蹈你已故的小情人的覆辙。
All right, all right, avoid the fate
of your late beloved boyfriend.
警笛声
(police siren)
鸽子声
(doves coo)
他是拉皮条的？
Was he your pimp?
什么？
What?
好的，这样来吧。
All right, play it that way.
起来吧，你只是头撞了一小下，
你还活着呢。
Come on, you've just got a little bump
on your head. You'll survive it.
你叫什么？
What's your name?
你不叫无名氏，对吧？
You got a name, don't you?
好吧，到派出所再问她名字。
All right, we'll settle this
at the station house.
-罗伯塔。
-罗伯塔，是个名字。
- Roberta.
- Roberta. That's a name.
你们搞错了。
I'm not who you think I am.
这些鸟你怎么用？
How do you use the birds?
你有个好房子，加里。
Nice place you got here, Gar.
我们都喜欢。
We like it.
挺结实。
Firm.
嗯，是。
Y-Yeah.
那是罗伯塔的。
They're Roberta's.
《社交指南》
"How To Be Your Own Best Friend."
《夫妻指南》
"I'm OK - You're OK."
《性爱指南》
"Dr Ruth's Guide To Good Sex."
这些也是罗伯塔的？
Are these Roberta's, too?
我不知道她在读这些。
I didn't know she read this stuff.
你知道吗，加里，在你我之间，
You know, Gar, between you and me,...
你真的了解罗伯塔什么？
...what do you really know about Roberta?
漂亮的墙纸。
Nice wallpaper.
在你翻她的衣服之前，
Don't you think
you ought to wait for Roberta...
你不觉得你应该等罗伯塔回来吗？
...before you start taking her clothes?
她欠我一件外套。
She owes me a coat.
-她体重多少？
-罗伯塔？
- What does she weigh?
- Roberta?
105, 110.
我们差不多，非常接近。
We're close. Very close.
-漂亮的浴缸。
-你喜欢？
- Nice tub.
- You like it?
那是，呃，这是我们众多受大众喜爱的款项之一。
That's, uh...
It's one of our most popular items.
你可以安装在所有的浴室里，
而且会为您的房子增价。
You can install it in any bathroom and it
increases the resale value of your home.
我没说我要买一个。
I didn't say I wanted to buy one.
是啊，不好意思。
Right. Sorry.
你要知道，我可以习惯这样的地方。
You know, I could get used
to a place like this.
来点大麻？
Got any pot?
大，大麻，呃…
P-pot. um...
平常我可以弄一些，
usually I keep some around,...
但是，现，现在，我要出去。
...but r-right now I'm out.
你应该明白。
You know how it is.
来一根火柴呢？
How about a match?
好，停。
(man) All right, stop.
脸向前。
Face forward.
笑一笑。
Smile.
左转
Turn left.
下一个。
Next.
然后你开始想…
And then you start to think,...
这都算什么呢？
...what's it all about?
一张大照片。你明白吗？
The big picture, you know what I mean?
我明白，加里。
Sure I do, Gar.
我是说，那…
I mean, there...
那有比赚钱更好的生活乐趣，对吗？
There's more to life
than making money, right?
我的意思是，我知道那个，我是说…
I mean, I know that. I mean...
哦，仫。
Oh... Mm.
你知道……
You know... You know how...
这一切是如何来源于
在大学时的一个单纯的想法？
...all time comes from
a single point in the universe?
-你明白我说的吗？
-不。
- You know what I mean?
- No.
我丈夫。
My husband.
我们住在李堡。
We live in Fort Lee.
-电话声。
-那些事情…
- (phone rings)
- There are...
…发生在太阳系很远的地方…
...things happening in solar systems
so far away...
…我们根本看不见它们。
...that we can't even see them.
笑
(giggling)
我是说，它们…它们在乎什么？
I mean, what do... what do they care?
它们在乎什么，即使我是纽泽西的矿泉浴巨擘？
What do they care
if I am the spa king of New Jersey?
喂，加里的家。
Hello. Glass house.
笑
(Gary giggles)
喂？
(Susan) Hello?
-喂？
-纽泽西矿泉浴的大王。
- Hello?
- Spa king of New Jersey!
笑
(Gary giggles)
矿泉浴大王。
Spa king!
我可以再打给别的人吗？求你了。
Could I call someone else? Please?
打吧。
Go ahead.
你，那个穿粉芭蕾舞裙的。
All right. You in the pink tutu.
该走了。
Let's go.
见到你真荣幸。
Nice to have met you.
她最好有一个好的解释。
She better have a good explanation!
你还没见到她就开始大叫。
You haven't seen her and you're yelling.
我不是。我就是想知道如果她有麻烦了
为什么不打个电话？
I am not! I am wondering aloud why she
couldn't have called if she was in trouble!
在你做任何蠢事之前先听听她是怎么说的！
Hear her side of it
before you do anything stupid!
格莱斯先生，Sergeant Taskal。坐下吧。
Mr Glass. Sergeant Taskal. Have a seat.
这是我姐姐莱斯莉。
My sister Leslie.
她在昨晚在下东区被逮捕。
She was arrested last night
on the Lower East Side.
她在一座水塔楼下，我马上把她带过来。
She's in a holding tank downstairs.
I'll have her brought up.
当我发现照片一样时，我立刻给你打了电话。
I telephoned you as soon
as I realised the photographs matched up.
嗨，Ronnie，我是Taskal。把格莱斯带来。
Hey, Ronnie. Taskal here.
Bring up Glass.
我们可以结案了，她丈夫来了。
We're dropping the charges.
Her husband is here.
是的，显然他还没接走她。
Well, obviously
he hasn't picked her up yet.
哦，罗伯塔。
(Gary) Oh, Roberta.
让我看看。
Let me see that.
哦，天啊。
Oh, my God.
格莱斯先生，不久之前有人交了你妻子的保释金，
她已经被放走了。
Mr Glass, somebody paid your wife's bail
a little while ago and she was released.
你就与她擦肩而过。
You just missed her.
谁，谁交了保释金？
Who-Who paid her bail?
男朋友，拉皮条的，你知道吗？
Boyfriend. Pimp. Who knows?
拉皮条的？
Pimp?
我不知道该怎么谢谢你，迪兹，
真的太不好意思了。
I don't know how to thank you, Dez.
I'm really sorry.
考虑到这是我最后一次帮你，苏珊，
Consider it my final favour, Susan.
你还真的没有辜负你的名声啊。
You are really living up
to your reputation.
看吧，现在已经完事了，迪兹。
See, now, that's just it, Dez.
结束了，我并不是你想的那个人。
That's it! I'm not who you think I am.
-我可不在乎你是谁。。
-不，不，我不是你说的那个意思。
- I don't care who you are.
- No, no, I didn't mean it that way.
这里真的很难讲明白，我不是…
It's really getting complicated here.
I'm not...
嘘。呆着别动。
Sssh. Stay right there.
这是怎么了？
I don't believe it.
天！
(Roberta) God!
我不敢相信维多利亚能这样做。
I don't believe Victoria would do this.
哦，天啊。
Oh, my God.
也许是昨晚抢我的那个人干的。
Maybe it was the guy
who grabbed me last night.
什么？
What?
抢你的那个人？
The guy who grabbed you?
你看，我跟踪了我，迪兹。
See, he was after me, Dez.
呃，并不是我，他跟踪苏珊…
Well, not me exactly.
He was after Susan,...
管她是谁，我不是！
...wherever she is, who I'm not!
他认为她住在这儿，可是那个她不在，
因为我是…
He thinks she's staying here,
which she isn't because I am...
我不想听！
I don't wanna hear it!
首先，我屁股被人扔在了人行道上。
First of all, I get thrown out
on my ass on the sidewalk.
接着，我不得不支付了200美元的保释金
把你从看守所里接出来。
Then I have to fork up $200 bail
to get you out of jail.
现在，我回家了，看到整个地方被撕的稀烂，
而为什么我还不知道！
Now I come home and the whole place
is torn apart. Why, I don't know!
你要知道，苏珊，我不想看到这些狗屁事，
真的不想。
You know, I really don't need this shit,
Susan. I really don't.
好。
Fine.
我走。
I'll leave.
哎呦！
Whoops!
你知道吗，迪兹，我昨天晚上可能会被人杀死了。
You know, I could have been killed
last night, Dez!
我真的怕得要命！
I was really scared!
别想了。
Forget it.
抱歉给你弄得这么乱。
Sorry about this mess.
我会赔给你，我会给你寄一张支票。
I can pay you back!
I'll send you a cheque.
很好，又一张支票。
Great. Another cheque.
哭
(sobbing)
对不起。
Sorry.
嘿嘿嘿，
Hey, hey, hey.
这么乱不是最坏的。
This mess isn't so bad.
我曾经开个派对，比着还要糟。
I've had worse parties than this.
笑
(Roberta giggles)
开电视
(turns TV on)
理查德・诺兰和布鲁斯・米克尔是在等待…
Richard Nolan and Bruce Meeker
were released...
…对他们1982年走私活动的定罪判决
提出上述期间被释放的。
...pending appeal of their 1982
conviction for smuggling.
他们是偷窃现在纽约展出的开罗收藏品中
They are prime suspects in the
disappearance of the Nefertiti earrings...
娜芙儿提提耳环的主要嫌疑人。
...from the Cairo collection
currently on display in New York.
娜芙儿提提？我靠！
Nefertiti? No shit!
这不正常！我刚刚看了一篇文章…
It's not uncommon!
I've just read an article...
…关于一个女人上午在城里胡作非为，
..about a woman who turned tricks
in the city all morning...
然后在下午回家前又恢复正常。
...and shopped all afternoon
before going home.
她做了好几年了，而她丈夫却一点不知道。
She did it for years
before her husband found out about it.
罗伯塔不可能去卖淫，她哪有妓女那样的性感身材？
这不可能。
Roberta can't be a prostitute. She doesn't
like sex that much. It's impossible.
哦，天啊，我可听说有五分之四的妓女是同性恋。
Oh, my God. I have heard that four
out of five prostitutes are lesbians.
莱斯莉，如果我妻子是同性恋的话我会知道的。
Leslie, I think that I would know
if my wife was a lesbian.
怎么知道？连她是妓女你都不知道。
Why?!
You didn't know she was a prostitute.
加里，我想你要接受这个事实…
Gary, I think you have
got to accept the fact...
就是在你的关系中存在着那些非常不正常的东西。
...that there is something very unusual
going on in your relationship.
苏珊
(Gary) Susan.
-苏珊。
-苏珊是谁？
- Susan!
- Who's Susan?
呃，别想歪了，她是来帮助我找罗伯塔的。
uh... Don't get the wrong idea.
She was helping me find Roberta.
苏珊。
(Gary) Susan!
Susan!
你在干什么？
What are you doing here?
我有好消息和坏消息，你要先听哪个？
I got good news and bad news.
What do you want first?
-你说过你会走的。
-好的，好消息。
- You said you were going to leave.
- OK, good news.
你妻子不是跟那油球一起的。
Your wife isn't with the greaseball.
苏珊，我妻子刚在下东区被人接走…
Susan, my wife has just been
picked up on the Lower East Side,...
……跟着她的带枪的拉皮条老板跑的！
...escaping from her gun-toting pimp!
他不是拉皮条的。
He's not a pimp.
-他不是拉皮条的。
- He's not a pimp.
坏消息是他有可能会杀了她，因为他认为她是我。
The bad news is he'll probably kill her
cos he thinks she's me.
-什么？
-你从来没读过吗？
- What?
- Didn't you ever read this?
她的日记。
She kept a diary.
有一些好定西:睡不着。
It's great stuff. "Couldn't sleep."
走进厨房，加里进来，关了灯。
"Went into kitchen.
Gary came in. Turned on light."
加里走了，剩下生日蛋糕。
"Gary left. Finished birthday cake."
这有好几页。这将是封底了。
没有人的生活会这样无趣。
Pages of it. It's gotta be a cover.
Nobody's life could be this boring.
你不该读这些的，这是私人隐私。
You shouldn't be reading that. It's private.
是啊，这个与她无关，而与我有关，听听这个。
Yeah, well, it's not about her.
It's about me. Listen to this.
他又开始找苏珊了，她从墨西哥州回来晚了。
"He's looking for Susan again.
She's late returning from Mexico."
这是他第五个启事了。
"This is his fifth ad."
为什么他如此强烈的想要见她？
她是谁？
"Why does he want to see her so badly?
Who is she?"
还有我的一张照片。
And there's my picture.
加里，为什么你不告诉我她读了这些启事呢？
Gary, why didn't you tell me
she read the personals?
我们昨天就可以搞定了。
We could've settled this yesterday.
她一直都在看这些启事。我不认为…
She read them all the time. I didn't think...
嗯，是。幸亏了每一个人，
我才能活下来想做点什么。
Yeah, well, fortunately for everybody,
I'm here and I'm thinking.
把车钥匙给我。
Give me the car keys.
我会把它完整带回来的。
I'll bring it right back.
嘿咻。
Hiya.
加里。她拿的是你的汽车钥匙。
Gary! She is taking the car keys!
别说了，莱斯莉，行吗？
Shut up, Leslie. OK?
日记本。有点偷偷摸摸的感觉。
她是怎么评论我的？
Diary. That little sneak,
what did she say about me?
疯狂寻找
陌生人寻找苏珊
"Desperately seeking
stranger seeking Susan."
敬启者，在星期六晚9点半，百老汇魔术俱乐部见。
"Regarding key. Meet me Saturday night,
Magic Club, Broadway. 9.30pm. Be there."
-就这些了？
-她会喜欢的。
- Is that it?
- She'll love it.
去柜台付钱。
Pay at the cashier.
四十岁单身白人男性，
寻找下午的玩伴。
"Single white male, 40,
looking for afternoon playmates."
就这些了？去柜台付钱。
Is that it? Pay at the cashier.
迪兹…
Dez...
我不是苏珊。
I'm not Susan.
我是家庭主妇，住在纽泽西李堡。
I'm a housewife
and I live in Fort Lee, New Jersey.
我已经结婚四年了。
I've been married for four years.
我丈夫加里…
My husband Gary...
他做浴盆和浴室的生意。
He sells bathroom spas and saunas.
你怎么还是这样？
You never stop, do you?
不，这是真的，真的。
No, really! Really!
这就是我喜欢你的原因，我从不知道你
下一句会说什么，过来。
That's why I like you. I never know
what you'll say next. Come here.
-门锁声
-迪兹。
- (door lock rattles)
- Dez.
-那是什么？
-不知道。
- What is that?
- I dunno.
有人想进来。
Someone's trying to get in.
哦，天啊。
Oh, my God.
哦，是吉姆。
Oh, my God, it's Jim.
天啊。
Oh, my God.
吉姆，吉姆。
Jim... Jim. Jim.
谢天谢地，你吓坏我了。你觉得怎么样，啊？
Thank God. You had me worried.
How you doing, man? Huh? Huh?
有人打我了，一片黑。
Somebody jumped me. It was dark.
嗯，呃…
Yeah. uh...
是我干的。
It was me.
我以为你是别人呢。
I thought you were somebody else.
你以为我是谁？
Who did you think I was?
有人跟踪了苏珊，我想你可能是他。
Somebody's been following Susan.
I thought maybe you were him.
谁跟踪她？
Who's following her?
不知道。
I don't know.
你知道苏珊。
You know Susan.
从她那里得到一个清楚的答案真是困难。
It's really tough
to get a straight answer out of her.
她需要我，迪兹。
She needs me, Dez.
我想或许她准备安顿下来了。
I think maybe she's ready to settle down.
安顿下来？苏珊？别扯了，吉姆。
Settle down? Susan? Come on, Jim!
她从没有做过什么安顿的事，
她不是那类人。
She'd never do that.
She's really not the type.
从什么时候你这么了解她？
Since when do you know her so well?
呃，我只是不能看见她安顿下来。
我是说，她太野性了。
Well, I just can't see her settling down.
I mean, she's too wild.
但是这也是她的魅力。
But that's what's so great about her.
是这样吗？
Is that so?
我是说，你真的好像对她做了一番检查。
I mean, you really seem
to have examined this.
嗯，我们一起度过了一些时间。
Well, we've been spending
some time together.
可…你在说什么呀，迪兹？
Just... what are you saying here, Dez?
啊？
Huh?
我不想对你胡说八道，吉姆。
I'm not gonna bullshit you, Jim.
是一件不好出口的事，
我没说它没有。
It was a shitty thing to do.
I'm not saying it wasn't.
但是你自己说她诱人的。
But you yourself said she was irresistible.
哦，不会吧。
Oh, man.
你，你为什么不再打我一下，就像这样的，
把我结果了？
W-why don't you just hit me again
and, like, finish me off?
-你看…
-啊？
- Look...
- Huh?!
别哭喊了。我真的为她而疯狂…
Don't cry about it.
I'm really crazy about her...
…而且她也为我而疯狂。
...and she's really crazy about me.
-我对不起，
-听着，我了解苏珊。
- I'm sorry.
- Listen. I know Susan.
无论她告诉什么都是胡扯。
Whatever she told you doesn't mean shit.
她不是认真的，迪兹。我是知道的，
我追了她好几年了。
She plays with people, Dez. I oughta
know, I've been chasing her for years.
我认为她跟我是认真的。
I don't think she's playing with me.
胡说。
Bullshit.
这样吧，吉姆。
All right, Jim.
我们干嘛不问问她呢？
Why don't we just ask her?
苏珊。
Susan!
苏…她在这儿？
Su...! You mean she's here?!
苏珊。
Susan!
-到这儿来。
-苏珊。
- Come on out here.
- Susan...!
苏珊。
Susan!
她走了。
She's gone.
她就在这儿。
She was here.
我发誓。
I swear to God.
水壶鸣响
(kettle whistles)
迪兹，你在上面吗？
(Jim) Dez, are you up there?
怎么了？
Yeah?
猜猜怎么了？
我想她把我俩都耍了。
Guess what, man?
I think she's jerking us both around.
你什么意思？
What do you mean?
你看看吧，这个他妈的陌生人是谁？
Check this out.
I mean, who the hell is this stranger?
鼓
(drum roll)
苏珊，我还是不明白我们来这儿干什么。
Susan, I still don't understand
why we're here.
信我吧，加里。你会惊喜万分的。
Trust me, Gar.
You're in for a real surprise.
你的惊喜万分已经让我紧张了。
Your surprises are beginning
to make me nervous.
-她怎么说？
-我们会惊喜万分的。
- What'd she say?
- We're in for a real surprise.
我想我们在这儿看不到Tony Bennett。
I guess we're not gonna see
Tony Bennett here.
我应该叫警察跟着我们。
I'd settle for a police escort.
你怎么能让她穿上罗伯塔的夹克？
How could you let her wear
Roberta's jacket?
嘿，她没衣服了，总得穿点什么吧。
Hey, she's cold.
She's gotta wear something.
为什么你不把你的指甲剪了？
(dummy) Why don't you
cut your fingernails?
我听不见你在说啥…
I can't hear what you're saying...
捂住叫喊
(muffled shouting)
迪兹，如果她看到我们俩都在这儿，
她很可能又一走了之。
Dez, if she sees us both here,
she'll probably just split again.
那你回去吧。
You could go home.
我要看看他妈的陌生人是谁。
I wanna see who this fuckin' stranger is.
让我猜。三倍龙舌兰到天亮。
Let me guess. Triple tequila sunrise.
姜味汽水。
Ginger ale.
你是威士忌。
And you're the Scotch.
这是你的。
This must be yours.
朗姆酒和Tab。
Rum and Tab.
坐着别动，我去找找陌生人。
Sit tight. I'm gonna
go look for the stranger.
什么陌生人？
What stranger?
-天，她可真迷人。
-一坨漂亮的屎罢了。
- God, she's gorgeous.
- Beauty feces.
她在那。
There she is.
-哪？
-就在那儿，和买烟女说话的那个。
- Where?
- Right there. Talking to the cigarette girl.
那不是苏珊。我之前从没见过那个女孩。
That's not Susan.
I never even seen that girl before.
迪兹，那是苏珊。你认为我能搞错吗？
Dez, that's Susan.
Don't you think I should know?
那可能是苏珊，但不是我的苏珊。
That might be a Susan
but that's not my Susan.
-那是我的苏珊。
-那么在巴特利公园的女孩是谁？
- That's my Susan.
- Then who was the girl at Battery Park?
谁是陌生人？
So who's the stranger?
吉米！
Jimmy!
谁是陌生人？
Who's the stranger?
-说来话长。
-嗯啊。
- It's a long story.
- uh-huh.
你怎么也不会知道她的。
You wouldn't know her anyway.
-她？
-是，她。
- Her?
- Yeah. Her.
过来，找个私人空间去说话。
Come on. We'll talk about it in private.
敲门
(knocking)
我们还有三分钟上场。
We've got three minutes before curtain!
戴上你的假发马上出发。
Get your wig on and get out there!
我在想苏珊会不会出事。
I wonder what happened to Susan.
看起来像是你丢了女友。
Looks like you lost your girlfriend.
嘿，赖瑞，我结婚了，懂吗？
Hey, Larry! I'm married, all right?
-哦，得了吧。
-怎么？
- Oh, please!
- What?
乐队声
(band plays fanfare)
晚上好，女士们先生们。
Good evening, ladies and gentlemen.
欢迎来到魔术俱乐部，我是主持人，雷。
Welcome to the Magic Club.
I'm your host, Ray...
酒吧生，给我结帐吧。
Bartender...
Can I have the check, please?
有谁从女皇区出来的吗？
Hey, is there anyone out here
from, uh... Queens?
你。好的。我自己是从正常人家的肚子里出来的。
You. Well, I'm from
normal parents myself.
零星笑声
(scattered laughter)
是这样的，今晚我们给大家一个特别的待遇。
Anyway, we got a special treat
for you people this evening.
让我介绍一下独一无二的，举世无双的…
Introducing the one, the only...
苏珊，快上来。
Susan, get up here!
…还有他可爱的助手，Davina…
...and his very lovely assistant, Davina...
…今夜女王，鼓掌吧。
...Queen of the Night! So let's hear it!
加里，那是…
(Leslie) Gary... Is that...
不会吧。
It can't be.
我太喜欢了，真是好魔术啊。
I'm really enjoying this. It's a great trick.
苏珊？
Susan?
-罗伯塔？
-我不敢相信。
- Roberta?
- I don't believe it.
-罗伯塔…
-加里，坐下。
- Roberta...
- Gary, sit down.
呃，我在这儿呆会儿，谢谢。
uh... I think I'll be staying, thank you.
鼓
(drum roll)
烟，要烟吗？
Cigars? Cigarettes?
她还是很有型的啊。
She's really got style in a way.
她很不错啊，加里。
She's good, Gary.
哦，对不起。
(Larry) Right. Sorry.
尖叫
(Roberta screams)
(screams)
哇哦！
Bravo!
是他，就是他。
That's him. That's the guy.
就是他！
That's the guy!
嗨，救救我。
Hey, help me!
嘿，就是他，就是他，救命。
Hey! That's the guy!
That's the guy! Help!
来人抓住他，帮帮我。
Somebody stop that guy! Help!
怎么…罗伯塔。
What... Roberta!
-罗伯塔。
-你是谁？
- Roberta!
- Who are you?
怎么了？
What's going on?!
-他打伤你了？我杀了他。
-加里。
- Did he hurt you? I'll kill him!
- Gary!
-没事了，我现在可以搞定了。
-这人是谁？
- It's OK, I can take care of it now.
- Who is this guy?
你是谁？你什么意思，我是谁？
Who are you?
What do you mean, who am I?
-拜托…
-哦。
- Please...
- Oh.
加里，迪兹。
Gary... Dez.
迪兹，他是加里，我丈夫。
Dez, this is Gary, my husband.
嗨。
Hi.
-做热水盆的生意人？
-是。
- The hot-tub salesman?
- Yeah.
这么说你昨晚告诉我的是真的了。
So you were telling me
the truth last night.
昨晚？哦，不。
Last night? Oh, no.
-你和他过了一夜？
-加里…
- Did you spend the night with him?
- Gary...
-他就是警察提到的拉皮条的？
-他不是拉皮条的。
- Is he the pimp the police mentioned?
- He's not a pimp!
我不是拉皮条的，我是她一个朋友。
I'm not a pimp. I'm a friend of hers.
-有谁呢能告诉我发生什么了？
-我自己都不知道。
- Somebody tell me what's going on!
- I'm not sure myself.
-这段时间我糟糕透了…
-我也是。
- I'm having a hard time...
- So am I!
先停一停，停一停。
Wait a minute! Wait a minute!
Please, wait a minute, wait a minute.
听我说。
OK, listen.
迪兹，迪兹，我需要和加里单独谈一谈，好吗？
Dez. Dez, I really need to talk
to Gary alone, OK? Please?
好吧。
OK.
我也需要自己静一静。
I really need some time alone too.
对不起。
I'm sorry.
都过去了，没事了，噩梦结束了。
It's all right. It's all right.
The nightmare's over.
弹球机
(pinball machine pinging)
别吱吱叫，你要把我带出去。
Don't make a peep.
You're gonna get me outta here.
低叫
(Susan whimpers)
腿不错。
Nice legs.
-我不明白你和那个家伙为什么会在这儿。
-你又为什么在这儿？
- I don't understand why you're here.
- Why are you here?
等等，先别管那个，你为什么离开我？
Wait a minute. Never mind that.
Why did you leave me?
那是某种意外的事。
It was sort of an accident.
意外？当你在拉客也是个意外了？
When you were soliciting,
that was an accident, too?
是的，当然是，加里。
Yes, of course! Gary!
一切都是从寻人启事开始的。
It all started with the personals.
那是给苏珊的广告，《不顾一切找苏珊》。
There was this ad for Susan.
"Desperately seeking Susan."
他到哪里去了？
Where did he go?
所以他们就认为我是个妓女而把我逮捕了。
So they thought
I was a prostitute and arrested me.
罗伯塔，你是同性恋吗？
Roberta, are you a lesbian?
莱斯莉说很多妓女都是同性恋。
Leslie said
lots of prostitutes are lesbians.
加里，你没有听我在说什么，
我不是妓女，也不是同性恋。
Gary, you're not listening to me.
I'm not a prostitute or a lesbian!
我们需要找专业人员来帮助你，
我不管那要花多少钱。
We'll get professional help.
I don't care how much it costs.
-我只要你现在跟我回家。
-为什么？
- I just want you to come home with me.
- Why?
为什么？你什么意思，为什么？
Why? What do you mean, why?
为什么你要我跟你一起回家？
Why do you want me
to come home with you?
拜托，别那么激动，行吗？
Come on, don't get excited, all right?
你是吸毒了还是吃什么了？
What, are you on drugs
or something now?
天啊。
God.
看着我。
Look at me.
我看着呢，你看起来像个怪物。
I looked at you. You look ridiculous.
我是说看着我，加里，看着我。
I mean look at me, Gary.
Look at me.
我不和你一起回家。
I'm not coming home with you.
你只不过是累了。
You're just tired.
为什么你不换套衣服，然后我们在家中讨论这个？
Why don't you get changed
and we'll talk about it at home?
来吧，来吧。
Come on. Come on.
很好，这很好。
Fine. That's fine.
呃，我先去外边，我只等你五分钟。
uh... I'm gonna go outside
and I'm gonna wait for five minutes.
如果你不过来，我就自己走了。
And if you're not there,
I'm gonna leave without you.
再见，加里。
Goodbye, Gary.
嘿，哇！
Hey! Whoa!
你从哪里得到的？
Where did you get this?
别动。
Stay!
苏珊，这是怎么回事？
Susan, what's going on?
救救我。
(whispers) Help me!
别推我。
Don't push!
动作好快，陌生人。
Good goin', stranger.
苏珊。
Susan.
-嗨。
-笑
- Hi.
- (giggling)
怎么了？
What's going on?
朋友们，现在是决战时刻了。
My friend, this is the crucial moment.
我们把主力转移到船上。
Our force field power plant
has been transferred to the ship.
我们的防线在敌人最薄弱的地方，
完全可以视实际情况而机动作战。
Our defences are at their weakest,
almost fully automatic.
突然袭击的成功可能性是非常大的。
The likelihood of a successful
mutant attack is at its strongest.
-并且他们可能没有意识到。
-我们努力保持这种状况…
- But they may be unaware.
- We've tried to keep them away...
哎呦。
Ow!
-嗨。
- Hi.
你怎么样了？
Huh. How are you doin'?
还行。
OK.
那么我猜你的名字不叫苏珊，啊？
So I guess your name isn't Susan, huh?
那么是什么？
So what is it?
罗伯塔。
Roberta.
-罗伯塔。
-嗯。嗯。
- Roberta.
- Mm-hm.
多好的名字。
That's nice.
多好的一对！
WHAT A PAIR!